<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<!DOCTYPE TEI [<!ENTITY List_Type SYSTEM 'List_type.xml'>]>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="eng">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <!-- TITLE & AUTHOR STATEMENT-->
                <!-- In this case anonymous -->
                <title>DIY guide to preventing sexual assault</title>
                <author>anonymous</author>
            </titleStmt>

            <editionStmt>
                <!-- EDITION STATEMENT -->
                <edition>TEI assignment 2</edition>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>encoded by</resp>
                    <!-- I tried to put the link to the github somewhere more fitting, but I did not find.  -->
                    <persName ref="https://github.com/Anarchiviste/TEI-assignment2.git">
                        <surname>Musquin</surname>
                        <forename>Jules</forename>
                    </persName>
                </respStmt>
            </editionStmt>

            <publicationStmt>
                <!-- DISTRIBUTOR & AVAILABILITY STATEMENT-->
                <distributor>
                    <persName ref="https://github.com/Anarchiviste/TEI-assignment2.git">
                        <surname>Musquin</surname>
                        <forename>Jules</forename>
                    </persName>
                    <date when="2025-11-13"/>
                </distributor>
                <availability>
                    <licence>
                        <p>Free. Copy and distribute at will !</p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier
                        source="https://archive.org/details/DiyGuideToPreventingSexualAssault/mode/2up">
                        <repository>Internet Archive</repository>
                        <idno>ark:/13960/t75t76r2h </idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        &List_Type;
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <front>
            <titlePage type="titlepage" n="1" rendition="#printed">
                <docTitle rend="black_ink white_background">
                    <titlePart type="main">A d.i.y guide to <lb/>preventing sexual
                        <lb/>assault</titlePart>
                </docTitle>

                <figure>
                    <figDesc>A black and white printed picture with a groupe of 6 young
                        peoples</figDesc>
                </figure>
                <imprimatur>Free. Copy and distribute at will!</imprimatur>
            </titlePage>
        </front>
        <body>
            <div1 n="2">
                <quote rendition="#printed" rend="black_ink white_background">"Once a girl knows I'm
                    going to <lb/>listen to a <emph>no</emph>, she knows I'm <lb/>going to listen a
                        <emph>yes</emph>, too. <lb/>That <emph>yes</emph> is a really nice thing
                    <lb/>to hear when she means it. Not <lb/>just about sex...About
                    <lb/>anything."</quote>
                <div2>
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>A black and white printed picture of a young man</figDesc>
                    </figure>
                </div2>
                <trailer rendition="#manuscript" rend="black_ink white_background"> It is up <lb/>to
                    each of us <lb/>to prevent <lb/>sexual <lb/>assault <lb/>in our
                    <lb/>community</trailer>
            </div1>
            <div1 n="3" rendition="#manuscript" rend="black_ink white_background">
                <head>Help a survivor</head>
                <list>
                    <!-- Item are an automatic line reset so I didn't use <lb/> at the beginning of an item -->
                    <item>Believe what your friend is telling you.</item>
                    <item>Dont pressure or force them to do <lb/>anything. They need to feel they are <lb/>in
                        charge of decisions.</item>
                    <item>Tell your friend that the rape is <emph>NOT</emph>
                        <lb/>their fault. Do not blame your friend <lb/>for what happened.</item>
                    <item>Don't question their behavior or <lb/>reasons.</item>
                    <item>Ask them how you can help, ask them <lb/>what they want.</item>
                    <item>Encourage them to go to a hospital <lb/>to get a rape kit done.</item>
                    <item>Rape is a crime, encourage them to <lb/>report it.</item>
                    <item>Encourage them to think about talking <lb/>to a counselor.</item>
                    <item>Support your friends. Listen to <lb/>their story and their needs. Don't
                        <lb/>be judgmental.</item>
                </list>
                <trailer>The <orgName>RAPE, ABUS &amp; INCEST NATIONAL <lb/>NETWORK</orgName>
                    hotline can redirect you <lb/>to a local crisis center. <address>
                        <idno>1-800-656-HOPE</idno>
                    </address> Make your community aware of <lb/>the resources in your area.
                </trailer>
            </div1>
            <div1 n="4" rendition="#printed" rend="black_ink white_background">
                <head>What to do if... <lb/>you or a friend are <lb/>sexually assaulted</head>
                <list>
                    <item>Go to a safe place. With people <lb/>you feel comfortable with.</item>
                    <item>Go to a hospital right away for a rape kit; <emph>DO NOT</emph> bathe,
                        douche, <lb/>shower, or change clothes before <lb/>hospital visit. Cleaning,
                        although <lb/>that may be your first instinct, <lb/>will destroy evidence
                        that could <lb/>be used if you decide to prosecute <lb/>the offender.</item>
                    <item>Talk to a legal advocate to decide <lb/>whether or not you should file a
                        <lb/>report.</item>
                    <item>Utilize the resources in your <lb/>community to help you cope with the
                        <lb/>assault.</item>
                    <item>Remember ! The rapist is entirely responsible <lb/>for a rape. A survivor <lb/>is
                        never at fault or to blame, <lb/>regardless of the situation.</item>
                    <item>If your friend has been assaulted, <lb/>stand by them, listen and do anything
                        <lb/>you can to help.</item>
                </list>
            </div1>
            <div1 n="5" rendition="#manuscript" rend="black_ink white_background">
                <p>Spread equality !</p>
                <div2>
                    <figure>
                        <figDesc>An A for anarchist, written in Gothic script, surrounded by a
                            heart</figDesc>
                    </figure>
                </div2>
            </div1>
            <div1 n="6" rendition="#printed" rend="black_ink white_background">
                <div2>
                    <head>Take care of yourself</head>
                    <p><lb/>- Communicate with your partner. Ask <lb/> questions to make sure the
                        two of <lb/>you see eye to eye. Really listen <lb/>to what your partner
                        says, it's <lb/> easy to hear what you want instead <lb/> of what they are
                        saying. Strop right <lb/>away if they say 'no' at any time.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Be smart about alcohol. It's much <lb/>easier to be a victim or
                        predator <lb/>when you're trashed.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Consent <emph>CANNOT</emph> be given while <lb/>drunk, high, passed
                        out or <lb/>emotionally distressed.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Be clear and assertive. If there is <lb/>any misunderstanding stop
                        teasing <caesura/><lb/>say <emph>no</emph>. Respect <emph>yourself</emph>,
                        it's<lb/> always OK to say no. It's OK to <lb/> change your mind. Sex is
                        never an <lb/> obligation.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Remember; there is no way that <lb/> anyone can dress that
                        invites<lb/>harrassement.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Avoid any situation you're not <lb/> completely comfortable with, and
                        <lb/>don't be afraid to leave any <lb/>situation that you feel is shady.</p>
                </div2>
                <div2>
                    <head>Take care of your friends</head>
                    <p><lb/>- Keep an eye on your friends. Don't <lb/>be afraid to step in and
                        intervene <lb/>if they are in a risky or bad <lb/>situation.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Making your presence know will let <lb/>your friend know that they are
                        not<lb/> alone and the person bothering them <lb/>may back off.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- Check in with your friends. If you <lb/>sense that they are
                        uncomfortable <lb/>with what's going on, step in and <lb/>make sur
                        everything is alright.</p>
                    <p><lb/>- If your friends are acting sketchy <lb/>or aggressive giving people
                        <lb/>unwanted/inappropriate attention. <lb/>don't be afraid to distract them
                        or <lb/>get them out of the situation. Be<lb/> sure to let them know that
                        their <lb/> Behavior was unacceptable.</p>
                    <figure>
                        <head>OPPOSE AND CONFRONT HOMOPHOBIA, <lb/> TRANSPHOBIA AND GENDER
                            OPPRESS<caesura/>ION! ATTITUDES FOSTER AN <lb/> ENVIRONNEMENT THAT ALLOW
                            SEXUAL <lb/>ASSAULT TO TAKE PLACE.</head>
                        <figDesc>A black and white printed photography of an young woman doign a
                            signe with her hands.</figDesc>
                        <quote>Nobody ever died of blue-balls, <lb/>cowboy. There's a lock on the
                            <lb/>bathroom door for a reason.</quote>
                    </figure>
                </div2>
            </div1>
            <div1 n="7" rendition="#printed" rend="black_ink white_background">
                <div2>
                    <div3>
                        <head>WHAT IS SEXUAL ASSAULT ?</head>
                        <p>Hearsay and speculation about date rape and sexual assault</p>
                        <figure>
                            <figDesc>3 pictures of 3 youngs men, anonimized by a black bar on their
                                eyes and quotes of them under each pictures.</figDesc>
                        </figure>
                        <quote><lb/>Some guys get loaded <lb/>and take advantage of <lb/>girls. Then
                            say, <lb/><quote>We were drunk, what's <lb/> the big deal
                            ?</quote></quote>
                        <quote><lb/>A friend of mine <lb/>sexually assaulted <lb/>someone, and I
                            feel <lb/> really betrayed- I <lb/>mean who can I <lb/>trust ?</quote>
                        <quote><lb/>When I hear about a rape close to me, I <lb/> feel powerless and
                            <lb/>stunned. I wonder if <lb/>I could have done anything to prevent
                            <lb/>it.</quote>
                    </div3>
                    <div3>
                        <head>HERE'S THE FACTS ...</head>
                        <p><lb/><emph>What is sexual Assault ?</emph>
                            <lb/>When .</p>
                        <p><lb/><emph>Whatg is Date or Acquaintance Rape?</emph>
                            <lb/>When someone you know or are on a <lb/>date with forces you to have
                            sexual <lb/>contact or intercourse.</p>
                        <p><lb/>Consent is ... <lb/>Giving your okay, verbally and
                            unimpei<caesura/>red (IE : <emph>NOT</emph> high or drunk) with full
                            awareness of your surroundings is <lb/>consent. Forcing or coercing
                            someone <lb/>into sexual activity or engaging in a <lb/>sexual act with
                            someone who is high,<lb/>drunk, passed out,or unable to give
                            <lb/>consent is rape.</p>
                    </div3>
                </div2>
            </div1>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
